GIANNI TALLARITA

DATA SCIENTIST ▼ TORCHIARA, ITALY, (RELOCATING TO BARCELONA, SPAIN) \$\cup +393515506523\$

• DETAILS •

Torchiara , Italy (relocating to Barcelona, Spain) +393515506523 gianni2k@gmail.com

• LINKS •

Personal Website + Portfolio

LinkedIn

• SKILLS •

SQL

Machine Learning

Python

Wolfram Language

• LANGUAGES •

English

Spanish

Italian

PROFILE

Data-Scientist, Machine Learning Engineer and Theoretical Physics PhD researcher with over 30 published papers. Experienced in using Machine Learning for advanced problems. Certified cloud associate for both Azure and AWS. Certified LLM training. Python, SQL and Wolfram language expert.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Associate Professor at Universidad Adolfo Ibáñez, Santiago de Chile

April 2015 — Present

Associate Professor of theoretical Physics. Responsible for teaching undergraduate/postgraduate courses and research. Raised over 200k USD in research funding. Won "Best Young Researcher" prize twice. Supervised 2 Master Thesis students and a PhD student.

PostDoctoral Researcher at Centro Estudios Cientificos (CECs), Valdivia

October 2013 — April 2015

Carried out Research in String Theory.

PostDoctoral Researcher at Universidad Nacional de La Plata, La Plata

April 2012 — April 2013

Carried out Research in String Theory.

Summer Intern at Bank of America, London

June 2008 — September 2008

Technology operations at Bank of America (implementations of automation processes via coding).

Systems Engineer at UltraElectronics, Cambridge

June 2006 — September 2006

Systems architecture testing. Development of anti-noise systems on commercial aeroplanes.

EDUCATION

PhD, Queen Mary University of London, London

October 2008 — January 2012

Masters of Science, University of Cambridge, Cambridge

March 2004 — September 2008

Masters in Data Science, Universidad Adolfo Ibáñez, Santiago

March 2023 — Present

CERTIFICATES

Azure ML Associate, Microsoft

AWS Cloud Practitioner, Amazon

Large Language Models: Application through Production, edX / Databricks